Hi, my name is David Brown and this is a reading writing class.
مرحباً، اسمي ديفيد براون وهذا درس في القراءة والكتابة.
Persuasive in your communication be useful for you, your studies, your future
أن تكون مقنعاً في تواصلك سيكون مفيداً لك، لدراستك، لمستقبلك
career, and etc.
المهني، إلخ.
Being more persuasive in your communication be useful for you.
أن تكون أكثر إقناعاً في تواصلك سيكون مفيداً لك.
To be more persuasive means to be able to get other people to do what you want.
أن تكون أكثر إقناعاً يعني أن تكون قادراً على جعل الآخرين يفعلون ما تريد.
To do what you want, exactly.
أن يفعلوا ما تريد، بالضبط.
How to be more persuasive?
كيف تكون أكثر إقناعاً؟
Well, you have to learn, they say, once I heard, once you know the crowd you are talking to,
حسناً، عليك أن تتعلم، كما يقولون، سمعت مرة، بمجرد أن تعرف الجمهور الذي تتحدث إليه،
you have to learn how to talk the same way they talk so they can understand you better.
عليك أن تتعلم كيف تتحدث بنفس الطريقة التي يتحدثون بها حتى يتمكنوا من فهمك بشكل أفضل.
But at the same time, with their same words, with the same way they talk,
ولكن في نفس الوقت، بنفس كلماتهم، وبنفس الطريقة التي يتحدثون بها،
you have to teach them something.
عليك أن تعلمهم شيئاً ما.
And once you teach, they can be able to follow you.
وبمجرد أن تعلمهم، سيكونون قادرين على اتباعك.
I think everyone has something that they can persuade us of if they just have the ability
أعتقد أن كل شخص لديه شيء يمكن أن يقنعنا به إذا كان لديه القدرة
to do that, those communication skills to talk and express themselves well.
على فعل ذلك، تلك المهارات التواصلية للتحدث والتعبير عن أنفسهم بشكل جيد.
It's not easy.
ليس الأمر سهلاً.
No, it's not easy, I agree.
لا، ليس سهلاً، أتفق معك.
It can be difficult.
قد يكون صعباً.
And this is something that we can improve.
وهذا شيء يمكننا تحسينه.
We can learn how to be more persuasive in our communication.
يمكننا أن نتعلم كيف نكون أكثر إقناعاً في تواصلنا.
And something that Frederick Douglass teaches us about, if you read his autobiography and we'll
وهذا شيء يعلمنا إياه فريدريك دوغلاس (Farīdrīk Dūghlās)، إذا قرأت سيرته الذاتية وسنقرأ
read a section of it today, you'll notice just how persuasive he is.
جزءاً منها اليوم، ستلاحظ كم هو مقنع.
He's just a really good writer, a really great persuasive writer for this cause.
إنه حقاً كاتب جيد جداً، كاتب مقنع عظيم من أجل هذه القضية.
And his words made a big impact because he was so persuasive.
وكان لكلماته تأثير كبير لأنه كان مقنعاً جداً.
So recap here, who was Frederick Douglass exactly?
إذن، لنلخص هنا، من كان فريدريك دوغلاس بالضبط؟
You can see a collage of images here.
يمكنكم رؤية مجموعة من الصور هنا.
This is from the pre-civil war, civil war era.
هذه من فترة ما قبل الحرب الأهلية، ومن عصر الحرب الأهلية.
You can see other examples of abolitionists in this photo here.
يمكنكم رؤية أمثلة أخرى لدعاة إلغاء العبودية (du'āt ilghā' al-'ubūdiyya) في هذه الصورة هنا.
So he was born in 1818 and died in 1895.
لقد ولد عام 1818 وتوفي عام 1895.
Of his prime was during the Civil War, he was an African-American social reformer, abolitionist,
كانت ذروة نشاطه خلال الحرب الأهلية، لقد كان مصلحاً اجتماعياً أمريكياً من أصل أفريقي، وداعية لإلغاء العبودية،
or writer, writer, and statesman.
وخطيباً (khaṭīban)، وكاتباً، ورجل دولة.
Can you read this part for us here?
هل يمكنك أن تقرأ لنا هذا الجزء هنا؟
After escaping from slavery in Maryland, he became a national leader of the abolitionist movement.
بعد هروبه من العبودية في ماريلاند، أصبح زعيماً وطنياً لحركة إلغاء العبودية.
Famous for his powerful speeches and writings?
مشهور بخطاباته وكتاباته القوية؟
Excellent. In fact, Abraham Lincoln knew about this man and had read his writings.
ممتاز. في الواقع، كان أبراهام لينكولن يعرف عن هذا الرجل وقرأ كتاباته.
And it was some of his writings that inspired him to go along with this movement.
وكانت بعض كتاباته هي التي ألهمته للانضمام إلى هذه الحركة.
So we have a chart here.
لدينا مخطط هنا.
We're going to think about what we know already about Frederick Douglass,
سنفكر فيما نعرفه بالفعل عن فريدريك دوغلاس،
maybe what I've told you already, or what you've heard before, or what you know about the
ربما ما أخبرتكم به بالفعل، أو ما سمعتموه من قبل، أو ما تعرفونه عن
Civil War already. What do you know already about this abolitionist or the Civil War?
الحرب الأهلية بالفعل. ماذا تعرفون بالفعل عن هذا الداعية لإلغاء العبودية أو عن الحرب الأهلية؟
From what you told me, well, he is an African-American, a slave.
مما أخبرتني به، حسناً، هو أمريكي من أصل أفريقي، كان عبداً.
He learned to read from others.
تعلم القراءة من الآخرين.
He wasn't taught how to read, but he learned from hearing other people how to read, right?
لم يُعلَّم كيف يقرأ، ولكنه تعلم من خلال سماع الآخرين يقرؤون، أليس كذلك؟
And he died of 77 years old, and he escaped from slavery in Maryland.
وقد توفي عن عمر يناهز 77 عاماً، وهرب من العبودية في ماريلاند.
And once he learned how to read, he was a famous .
وبمجرد أن تعلم القراءة، كان  مشهوراً.
He was a famous writer.
كان كاتباً مشهوراً.
Writer. Famous abolitionist and writer. Excellent.
كاتباً. داعية مشهور لإلغاء العبودية وكاتب. ممتاز.
You're a good listener. Thank you.
أنت مستمع جيد. شكراً لك.
Now, there are new things to learn here. What questions do you have about Frederick Douglass?
الآن، هناك أشياء جديدة لنتعلمها هنا. ما هي أسئلتك حول فريدريك دوغلاس؟
What kind of things would you like to know about him?
ما هي الأشياء التي تود أن تعرفها عنه؟
Oh.
أوه.
Okay, it says that he escaped from slavery. Why did he do after that?
حسناً، يُقال إنه هرب من العبودية. ماذا فعل بعد ذلك؟
Yeah.
نعم.
And how do you think you'll find out? Well, I think we can find out through today's lessons and
وكيف تعتقد أنك ستكتشف ذلك؟ حسناً، أعتقد أننا يمكن أن نكتشف ذلك من خلال دروس وأنشطة اليوم،
activities, but actually what we're going to read today has more to do with his thoughts before
ولكن في الواقع ما سنقرأه اليوم يتعلق أكثر بأفكاره قبل أن يهرب.
he escaped. I still think you can have some idea about what he had to do or what led him to
ما زلت أعتقد أنه يمكنك تكوين فكرة عما كان عليه أن يفعله أو ما الذي دفعه إلى التمكن من الهروب.
being able to escape. And this is something else that maybe you'll be able to
وهذا شيء آخر ربما ستتمكن من قراءته
read after this lesson today as well if you'd like to finish reading his autobiography.
بعد درس اليوم أيضاً إذا كنت ترغب في إنهاء قراءة سيرته الذاتية.
And some of his writings. So we have some vocabulary that we need to focus on. We'll read a passage
وبعض كتاباته. إذن لدينا بعض المفردات التي نحتاج إلى التركيز عليها. سنقرأ مقطعاً
from Frederick Douglass's autobiography where he describes his determination to learn to read
من سيرة فريدريك دوغلاس الذاتية حيث يصف تصميمه على تعلم القراءة والكتابة.
and write. Nothing could stop this guy. He did everything he could to educate himself in
لا شيء يمكن أن يوقف هذا الرجل. لقد فعل كل ما بوسعه لتعليم نفسه
a world in which it was very taboo for a slave to learn to read and write.
في عالم كان فيه تعلم العبد للقراءة والكتابة من المحرمات الشديدة.
Okay. These are some vocabulary words that we need to know here. I'd like for you to take a look
حسناً. هذه بعض المفردات التي نحتاج إلى معرفتها هنا. أود منك أن تلقي نظرة
at these and their definitions. We have strategies. Can you read the definition for me here?
عليها وعلى تعريفاتها. لدينا "strategies" (استراتيجيات - istrātījiyyāt). هل يمكنك قراءة التعريف لي هنا؟
Clever tricks. Clever tricks are plans used to achieve a goal.
حيل بارعة. حيل بارعة (ḥiyal bāri'a) أو خطط (khuṭaṭ) تستخدم لتحقيق هدف ما.
Deprovity.
"Depravity" (فساد أخلاقي - fasād akhlāqī / انحطاط - inḥiṭāṭ).
I cannot see it out. Moral corruptions or wickedness. Wickedness.
لا أستطيع رؤيتها جيداً. فساد أخلاقي أو شر. شر.
About this one. Shuttle. In item of first, how do you pronounce it?
ماذا عن هذه. "Chattel" (متاع منقول - matā' manqūl / رقيق - raqīq). الكلمة الأولى، كيف تنطقها؟
Shuttle. Shuttle. It sounds like a French, right?
"Chattel". "Chattel". تبدو كأنها فرنسية، أليس كذلك؟
An item or personal property. In slave people were legally
مادة أو ملكية شخصية. الأشخاص المستعبدون كانوا قانونياً
considered shuttle. So it's basically like a worthless object. They were treated like just
يعتبرون "chattel" (متاعاً منقولاً). لذا فهو في الأساس مثل شيء لا قيمة له. لقد عوملوا كمجرد
objects, just things that could be used and thrown away. And this one precepts, precepts.
أشياء، مجرد أشياء يمكن استخدامها والتخلص منها. وهذه "precepts" (مبادئ - mabādi' / تعاليم - ta'ālīm). "Precepts".
Rules are principles guiding behavior. Apprehension.
قواعد أو مبادئ توجه السلوك. "Apprehension" (توجس - tawajjus / فهم - fahm).
You hear me.
هل تسمعني.
Apprehension. You hear me? Apprehension.
"Apprehension". هل تسمعني؟ "Apprehension".
Fear. Now I can. Fear and anxiety that something bad will happen. Also understanding.
خوف. الآن أسمعك. خوف وقلق من أن شيئاً سيئاً سيحدث. وأيضاً فهم.
No. Urchins.
لا. "Urchins" (أطفال شوارع - aṭfāl shawāri' / مشاغبون - mushāghibūn).
Urchins mischievous. No, I don't know how to pronounce it.
"Urchins" مشاغب. لا، لا أعرف كيف أنطقها.
Mischievous. Mischievous.
"Mischievous" (mischievous). "Mischievous".
Often poor and regularly closed children.
غالباً أطفال فقراء ويرتدون ملابس رثة.
They have sea urchins. Sea urchin is the type of sea creature with spikes on it.
هناك "sea urchins" (قنافذ البحر - qanāfidh al-baḥr). قنفذ البحر هو نوع من الكائنات البحرية ذات الأشواك.
But you can use them to describe children to urchins for good.
ولكن يمكنك استخدامها لوصف الأطفال أيضاً، "urchins"، بمعنى إيجابي أو محبب.
And this one, vindication. Vindication.
وهذه، "vindication" (تبرئة - tabri'a / إثبات صحة - ithbāt ṣiḥḥa). "Vindication".
And vindication. Clearing someone of blame. Oh, and suspicious. Proof that someone or something is
و "vindication". تبرئة شخص من اللوم. أوه، وإثبات. دليل على أن شخصاً ما أو شيئاً ما
right or reasonable. And a boy. A boy. To regard with disgust and hatred.
صحيح أو معقول. و "abhor" (يمقت - yamqutu / يكره بشدة - yakrahu bi-shidda). "Abhor". النظر باشمئزاز وكراهية.
And hatred.
وكراهية.
So we use this as a verb to abore something, to really hate something.
لذا نستخدم هذا كفعل، أن "abhor" شيئاً ما، أن تكره شيئاً ما بشدة.
So a lot of these words really highlight some of the things that we'll talk about through our
الكثير من هذه الكلمات تسلط الضوء حقاً على بعض الأشياء التي سنتحدث عنها من خلال
reading or read together. When we read, we'll try to focus on the meaning, although I can help you with
قراءتنا أو نقرأها معاً. عندما نقرأ، سنحاول التركيز على المعنى، على الرغم من أنني يمكن أن أساعدك في النطق،
pronunciation. I don't want it to.
لا أريد لذلك أن يعيق الفهم.